CHARLES ANESU KOMBO

+27 714 293 780 charleskombo070@gmail.com · https://www.linkedin.com/in/charles-anesu-kombo-b44677aa/

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

I am results-oriented Software Engineer with 4+ years experience in full life cycle software engineering and development. In these years I have designed, tested and maintained software systems in an Agile managed environments. I have knowledge in Typescript, Python and Ruby programming languages. I am also interested in cloud computing; AWS to be specific and I am practicing and learning towards a Solutions Architect certification.

KEY COMPETENCIES

Soft Skills

Communication · Teamwork · Problem Solving · Leadership · Adaptability · Emotional Intelligence

Technical Skills

React · React Native · Flutter · Typescript · Dart · Ruby · Apollo Federation · TDD · GraphQL · Jest · RSpec · Rest API · AWS · CI/CD

Software Engineer SOVTECH INTERNATIONAL |

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

April 2023 - Present

Working as a Software Engineer for the largest custom software development company in Africa

Responsibilities:

- High level and low level frontend and backend architecture of web and mobile applications
- Building scalable APIs using NodeJs
- · Sharpening cloud computing skills using our AWS sandbox
- Write clean typescript code in React, React Native and Nodejs to release features to production following the Agile Methodology
- · Unit Testing using Jest
- · End to End Testing using Cypress

Software Developer (Fullstack) SEON GROUP |

June 2019 - April 2023

Worked for a cloud-native alarm monitoring company in Germany

Responsibilities:

- Part of the team that built the inhouse mobile application and web application from design to deployment using React and React Native, Ruby On Rails, Apollo Federation and AWS services
- Developing APIs for the control room web app and responder mobile app to consume using Ruby on Rails
- · Led the Up skilling and Tech Talk sector in the company
- · Communication with clients to understand business and technical requirements
- Collaborate with cross-functional teams to develop and implement new software features

Freelance Developer SELF EMPLOYED

May 2021 - Present

Built some react, react native, NodeJS, Django and Flask applications for different clients

Responsibilities:

- Wrote clean code to deliver applications to clients on live environments
- · Communicated with clients to understand their requirements.
- Managed a small FE team to develop a mobile application across all OS
- · Deployed and maintained the applications using AWS

Intern/Junior Developer NONA DIGITAL (Now YOCO)

November 2018 - January 2020

Interned for a software development and design house

Developed the first version of the Web Application which was a digital rental platform that helped advertise properties, coordinate viewings, vet tenants, hold the deposit and lease agreement, handle maintenance and rent collection.

PROJECTS

ESTI - a real estate company

https://www.esti.com/ - This is their main web app that I built using NextJS. The free plan on the app shows a lot
of features

GIG OFFICE - a consulting startup

 https://gigoffice.africa/ -- I built this web application with React using Typescript. I also designed the platform on Figma

EDUCATION

University of Cape Town

Bachelor of Science in Computer Engineering and Computer Science

St Faiths Highschool Zimbabwe

A Level (Sciences)

VOLUNTEER WORK AND INTERESTS

LIONS CLUB INTERNATIONAL

Member

Greenpoint Tennis Club Cape Town

Member